Guide to the Forest Hills Gardens Corporation Records, 1922-1979, 1922-1958 (bulk)
Forest Hills Gardens Corporation Records
- Alphabetical Files
  - 1945-1950
    - Block 12
      - Block 12 Suit, 1928 (Box 29)
        Various legal papers and correspondence
- Series II. Vouchers, Permits, and Legal Documents
  - Vouchers
    - A - Vouchers/Receipts, 1938 (Box 22)
    - Atterbury Vouchers, 1938-1940 (Box 22)
    - B - Vouchers/Receipts, 1934-1943 (Box 22)
    - B - Vouchers/Receipts, 1938 (Box 22)
    - Vouchers/Receipts, 1939 (Box 22)
    - C Vouchers & Receipts, 1938-1939 (Box 22)
    - Underwood Elliott Fisher Company - Repair vouchers (Box 5)
    - Forest Hills Flower Shop, 1939-1943 (Box 4)
      Payroll and maintenance bills; vouchers
    - Flower Shop, 1938 (Box 4)
      Maintenance and payroll
    - G - Vouchers, 1939-1943 (Box 4)
    - G - Vouchers, 1938 (Box 4)
    - L.M. Green Vouchers, 1938 (Box 4)
      Receipts - detailed memo of requirements for submission and approval of architectural plans
    - L.M. Green Vouchers, 1943-1947 (Box 4)
    - H - Vouchers & receipts, 1938 (Box 4)
    - Herrick Garage Vouchers, 1940-1943 (Box 4)
      Gasoline, oil, servicing
    - I - Vouchers, 1943 (Box 4)
      Evening park guard vouchers (R. Ingrassia)
    - Insurance, 1937-1939 (Box 4)
      Policy memoranda and receipts
    - Insurance Vouchers, 1937-1939 (Box 4)
    - J - Vouchers & Receipts, 1939-1943 (Box 4)
    - J - Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 4)
    - K - Vouchers & Receipts, 1939-1943 (Box 4)
    - K - Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 4)
    - L - Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 4)
    - L - Vouchers & Receipts, 1938-1943 (Box 4)
    - Mc - Vouchers & Receipts, 1939-1943 (Box 4)
    - Mc - Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 4)
    - M Vouchers & Receipts, 1939-1943 (Box 5)
    - M Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 5)
    - New York and Queens Electric Light and Power Co., ca. 1944-1945 (Box 5)
      Vouchers for electricity of lights in Stabin Square, parks, Archway Place (merged in 1944-1945, to become Consolidated Edison of New York, Inc.)
    - N.Y. and Qu. Electric Light and Power Co. - Vouchers, 1939-1943 (Box 5)
      Vouchers for electric lights in special areas
    - N.Y and Qu. Electric Light and Power Co. - Vouchers for electric lights in special areas (Box 5)
    - P - Vouchers & Receipts, 1939-1943 (Box 5)
    - Petty Cash Vouchers & Receipts, 1939-1943 (Box 5)
    - Petty Cash Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 5)
    - Q Vouchers & Receipts, 1939-2943 (Box 5)
    - Q Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 5)
    - R Vouchers & Receipts, 1939-1943 (Box 5)
    - R Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 5)
    - Vouchers & Receipts, 1940-1943 (Box 5)
    - S - Vouchers & Receipts, 1938 (Box 5)
    - Social Security - Vouchers and receipts, 1939-1943 (Box 5)
    - Social Security Act - Withholding documents, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
    - T - Vouchers & Receipts, 1939 (Box 5)
    - Tax Vouchers - City of N.Y. occupancy, 1939-1943 (Box 5)
    - Unemployment Insurance Vouchers (Box 5)
    - Vouchers, 1938-1943 (Box 9)
      E.g.: Welsbach Lighting, office and plant repairs
  - Permits (to open streets or curb plots for making connections or repairs)
    Alphabetical by last name of owner
    - A Permits, 1923-1939 (Box 12)
    - B Permits, 1925-1939 (Box 12)
    - D Permits, 1924-1939 (Box 12)
    - E Permits, 1923-1939 (Box 12)
    - F Permits, 1925-1939 (Box 12)
    - G Permits, 1923-1939 (Box 12)
    - H Permits, 1926-1938 (Box 12)
    - I Permits, 1927-1936 (Box 12)
    - J Permits, 1923-1937 (Box 12)
    - K Permits, 1924-1939 (Box 12)
    - L Permits, 1924-1939 (Box 12)
    - Mc Permits, 1923-1938 (Box 12)
    - M Permits, 1924-1939 (Box 12)
    - O Permits, 1926-1939 (Box 12)
    - P Permits, 1923-1937 (Box 12)
    - Q Permits, 1929-1930 (Box 12)
    - R Permits - as above for "R" owners, 1923-1939 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous Permits I, 1923-1939 (Box 13)
      Various opening of Garden's property, i.e.: streets, curb plots, parks, Station Square, etc. for connections, repairs
    - Miscellaneous Permits II (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous Permits III (Box 13)
      Includes "S" owners
    - T Permits, 1926-1936 (Box 13)
    - U - XYZ Permits, 1923-1939 (Box 13)
  - Legal Documents
    - Unemployment Insurance, 1936-1938 (Box 9)
      Various documents, forms, correspondence
    - Forest Hills Dwellings vs. FHGC, 1934 (Box 21)
    - Architectural Submissions - Blue forms, 1930 (Box 21)
    - Extension Agreement for Restrictions, 1936 (Box 13)
      Ending 1950, unless renewed (agreement dated Aug. 24, 1944 ) - copies, working copies (no originals)
    - Assents to Agreement Renewing Restrictions (Box 26)
      For 1950 renewal, some assenting property owners agreements, working block maps, misc. working papers
    - Agreement Renewing Restrictions, 1944 (Box 26)
      (for 1950 ) correspondence, maps, ALSO: original copy of Agreement to Renew Restrictions and Covenants dated Aug. 24, 1944
    - Tax Matters, 1935-1937 (Box 28)
      Regarding taxes and assessments - (some from 1931 "T" file)
    - Office Procedures and Policies, 1959 (Box 29)
      Information for FHG office assistants
    - Summons and Injunctions, 1927-1939 (Box 29)
      Various court actions, FHG vs. miscellaneous defendants
    - Foreclosure for Collections in Arrears, 1934 (Box 29)
      Complaint to foreclosure maintenance lien against "James Jones et al" (draft of proposed form of action), action against various owners
- Series III. Maps, Plans, Oversized Items, Brochures, and Glass Plate Negatives
  - Maps, Plans, Oversized Items
    - Envelope of old maps (Box 6)
      Maps #1 and #2 and Tract 3, bought by Sage Co. between #2 and #3 (FHG west of Continental Avenue, except WSTC)
    - Map, 1911 (Box 21)
      Blueprint map of FHG. Sage Foundation Homes Company showing of original street names, Block and Lot Nos.
    - Map #3 - Progress map, Sept. 10, 1914 (Box 21)
    - Map #5 (Box 21)
    - Map #6 (Box 21)
      Showing by color properties under Four mill agreement
    - Map #6 (Box 21)
      Showing Parks and Lanes and City Tax Map Blocks
    - Map #6 - Corrected, Feb. 1921 (Box 21)
    - Map fragment - Undated, showing portion of FHG and Vanderveer Tract (Box 21)
    - Map of Forest Hills Court, Oct. 6, 1923 (Box 21)
      Auction map with lots to be sold Continental, Roman, Ascan Avenues; Harrow, Ingram and Juno Streets
    - Tract 2 Development (Box 21)
      Between Kessel Street and Metropolitan Avenue, Puritan and Ascan Avenues
    - Cantoni Plans -, 1952 (Box 29)
      Complete plans for house built at #244 Greenway North - architectural drawings, permits, correspondence (3 folders)
    - Oversized plans, Date unknown (Folder 1)
    - Large bound volume containing general information, Undated (Folder 2)
    - Large bound volume containing general information, Undated (Folder 3)
    - Drawings and plans, Date unknown (Folder 4)
  - Brochures
    - "79 Beautification Fund" - Brochure for fund raiser, 1979 (Box 14)
    - Commercial Brochures and Advertising Booklets, 1930s-1940s (Box 21)
    - Publications (Box 21)
      1. The Flushing Meadow Improvement, Jan. 1937.
      2. Neighborhoods for the City of Tomorrow in the World's Fair District - 1937 (from Mayor's Office).
      3. Jan. 1944 issue of Architectural Record containing articles about the Leslie Apartment
    - Forest Hills Gardens Booklets, 1916 (Box 27)
      Booklets containing preliminary information for buyers, published by Sage Foundation,
    - Captain Gerald MacDonald - A Biographical Memorial (Box 29)
      Leather bound volume prepared for MacDonald Family and privately printed by the American Historical Society, Inc. N.Y. 1930. Former Forest Hills resident (house may have been on site of present Kennedy House on Queens Boulevard)
  - Glass plate negatives
    A collection of early views of Forest Hills Gardens, 1913 to approximately 1920, primarily of the Forest Hills Inn, Station Square and Flag-pole Green at the time of the July 4th celebrations. Observance of this Holiday was very important and was a day long event beginning with a sunrise proclamation by a Town-crier dress in costume (see photo) and continuing with a parade, games, dances, speeches, and a flag raising ceremony at Flag-pole Green
    The Perry Collection #3442, 7-74 case 3, has a box with a collection of 37 lantern slides used by Mr. Perry for lectures on city planning Aug. 1, 1946. Fourteen of these slides are of Forest Hills Gardens, showing early views of Station Square dated July 1914 and of the July 4, 1914 celebration (similar to #28-41 in Box 30, #2775). Also, included is an early landscape overview of the Terraces (and Block 12) looking east from the Forest Hills Inn and an early view of the Olivia Park. A slide of an entrance gate to the Gardens is also included
    - 1 - The town crier (Box 30)
    - 2-27 - Spectators, games, races, flag raising ceremonies in Flag-pole Green on occasion of 4th of July celebration earlier - some Atterbury row houses visible on Greenway Terrances, ca. 1920 (Box 30)
    - 28-41 - July 4th celebration observances in Station Square and Forest Hills Inn area - speaker shown in #28 and #29, may be Teddy Roosevelt, a frequent visitor to Forest Hills Gardens, ca. 1920 (Box 30)
    - 42-72 - Young dancing girls performing outdoors in July 4th celebration events, ca. 1920 (Box 30)
    - 73 - B of 4 section Panorama (Box 30)
    - 74-76 - Early view Station Square, ca. 1913 (Box 30)
    - 77 - View from Burns Street towards Square, ca. 1930 (Box 30)
    - 78 - Early view from Terraces into Station Square ca., 1913 (Box 30)
    - 79 - Station Square, ca. 1920 (Box 30)
    - 80 - Station Square (Christmas tree in Square), ca. 1920 (Box 30)
    - 81-82 - Station Square, ca. 1920 (Box 30)
    - 83 - Detail of street sign (Box 30)
    - 84 - Street lantern affixed to Forest Hills Inn in Station Square area (Box 30)
    - 85 - Lantern light fixture near Forest Hills Inn in Station Square area (Box 30)
    - 86 - Greenway Terrace group of row houses (Atterbury), ca. 1920 (Box 30)
    - 87 - Early house, pre-1920 (Box 30)
    - 88 - Early house, pre-1920 (Box 30)
    - 89 - Early house (Box 30)
    - 90 - Early homes under construction, pre-1920 (Box 30)
    - 91 - Atterbury house corner of Greenway North and Overhill Road (Box 30)
    - 92 - Early grandstands at West Side Tennis Club before tennis stadium was built (Box 30)
    - 93 - Early photo of West Side Tennis Club before the stadium was built (Box 30)
    - 94 - Playground (Box 30)
    - 95 - Pathway and trees (Box 30)
    - 96 - Dogwood trees, May 1913 (Box 30)
    - 97 - Undeveloped property (Box 30)
    - 98 - Unidentified (Box 30)